Carolyn Dew

carolyndew@gmail.com 513 907 9531 www.carolyndew.com Atlanta, Ga.

Summary

ux professional with 3+ years experience in ux design and research, 6+ years in visual design, with a focus on collaborative techniques, honoring diverse perspectives, and user-centered practices.

Process Skills

Lean ux, Agile/Scrum, interaction design, usability testing, contextual inquiry, survey design, wireframing, rapid prototyping, information architecture, responsive design, web analytics, content strategy, writing user stories, collaborative design techniques, visual design, branding.

Technical Skills

Axure, Balsamiq, Adobe cc, HTML5, Mustache, css3, Less/Sass, Silverback, Bootstrap, Zurb's Foundation, et al. Familiarity with JavaScript, Json, jQuery, Git.

Work Experience

Expert Interaction Designer 2013 - current

Turner Broadcasting Systems, Inc., Atlanta, Ga.

- Responsible for spearheading UX design and research for an enterprise application that helps generate approximately \$4 billion in annual revenue across all divisions, including CNN, TBS, TNT, Cartoon Network, and TBS Sports.
- Identified product priorities through a variety of ux research techniques, including remote and inperson usability testing, contextual inquiry, survey design, and analytics.
- Introduced and facilitated collaborative design techniques within a cross-functional, Agile team.
- Developed interactive prototypes, wireframes, mock-ups, and user flows to rapidly validate design decisions, feature sets, and guide product development.
- Advocated for user needs in feature definition, milestone planning, story writing, and prioritization.
- Conducted departmental training and advocacy supporting ux in enterprise software.

Director of Visual Communications & Web Development 2012 – 2013 **Assistant Director for Marketing & Communications** 2010 – 2012

Future Educators Association, Pi Lambda Theta, and PDK International, Bloomington, Ind.

- Introduced the terminology, principles, and practices of user experience to the organization and advocated for their adoption.
- Spearheaded the complete redesign and adoption of a wcms platform for the Pi Lambda Theta website and online publication *Educational Horizons*, coordinating a cross-functional team of internal staff and outside vendors.
- Identified key user tasks in a full redesign of PDK membership renewal process. Defined user groups, storyboarded task flows, developed wireframes and defined interactions from a service design perspective.
- Led a collaborative effort on the PDK International website redesign. Defined project scope and strategy, developed information architecture, conducted a full content audit, and defined target audiences and user needs.
- Oversaw ongoing development and management of websites for three education professional associations, including online versions of their publications, collaborating with vendors and staff.
- Oversaw the hiring, training, and mentoring of a junior designer.

Freelance Graphic Designer 2004 – 2014

Various Locations

- Created innovative and practical solutions to visual communication problems, including visual identity, editorial design, signage, web design, email newsletters, and others.
- Led clients through the design process, present concepts, and facilitate productive discussions. Clients include the University of Cincinnati, Indiana University's School for Public and Environmental Affairs, APE Games, Bloomington Argentine Tango Organization, WFHB Community Radio, Bloomingfoods Market & Deli, and others.

www.carolyndew.com Atlanta, Ga.

Work Experience (continued)

Graphic Designer 2009 - 2010

Indiana Memorial Union at Indiana University, Bloomington, Ind.

- Designed program and event logos, print brochures, magazine and newspaper advertisements, online ads, hallway displays, digital display slides, email newsletters, and web content for one of the largest student unions in the country.
- Implemented Indiana University visual identity standards across all projects for strong branding.
- Wrote and edited copy for website, newsletters, and print material following AP and Indiana University style guides.

Communications Coordinator 2006 – 2007

Happen, Inc., Cincinnati, Ohio

 Managed, designed, and implemented a wide variety of print and web campaigns for this arts education nonprofit. Contributed to both writing and design.

Volunteer & Service

President 2009 – 2010,

Public Relations Officer, and Dance Instructor 2007 - present

Ritmos Latinos Indiana, Bloomington, Ind.

- Managed the efforts of volunteer teachers and officers who oversee all operations of this student organization comprising about 80 members, one of the largest dance groups on campus.
- Led collaborative initiatives to improve teaching and curriculum, event planning, and governance, utilizing feedback from members and facilitating group brainstorming sessions.
- Envisioned, planned, and organized the organization's first ever dance workshop with a nationally recognized visiting instructor.
- Provided advice and guidance to student officers. Offered feedback and training for volunteer instructors. Resolved conflicts between members.

Recognition

Grand Award for the Nov./Dec. 2012 issue of Go Teach, Communications Concepts APEX Awards, 2013

Award of Excellence for Pi Lambda Theta Career Resources Center (online resource), Communications Concepts APEX Awards, 2013

Award of Excellence for Go Teach magazine WordPress site, Communications Concepts APEX Awards, 2013

Silver Award for *Go Teach* magazine, Association Media and Publishing EXCEL Awards (Magazines: Cover, Mixed-Media), 2013

Shared Honorable Mention for Educational Materials, American Association of Museums' Publications Competition for work done with ArtWorks, Inc. in Cincinnati, 2007

Education

Master of Public Affairs in nonprofit management, Indiana University, 2010

Master of Arts in Journalism focusing on public relations, Indiana University, 2010

Bachelor of Fine Arts in graphic design, painting, and art history, Ohio University, 2004